Hi everyone, you're watching the drogram
show. I'm Ted R. Over there is CIA
whistleblower John Kuryaku. Uh we are
talking to you on Thursday, August 14th,
2025. Thanks so much for joining us. We
have a very short show today because
John's got a train to catch.
>> Sorry.
>> And I guess with the new regime in
Washington DC, which we'll be talking
about, the trains might be running more
on time than in the past. We'll explain
that. We're here. We've this week we are
here Monday, Wednesday, Friday 5: PM
except we weren't here yesterday. So,
but we will be back tomorrow at 5:00 PM.
Uh please like, follow and share the
show. Uh we will be next week
inaugurating our daily schedule Monday
through Friday, Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday for people
who are not familiar with the days of
the week at 5:00 p. p.m. Eastern time.
Thank you so much for supporting the
show. You guys are awesome. Since we do
have such a short time, John, let's just
get into it. Why don't you talk to a
little bit about uh what you encountered
in or what you what's going on in
Washington DC where uh the National
Guard has been federalized and the uh
Washington Metropolitan Police which is
the local police force has also been
federalized by Donald Trump ostensibly
to crack down on street crime.
>> Yeah. The thing is though there is no
street crime not in the parts of
Washington that that Donald Trump is
talking about. Yes, there are bad
neighborhoods in Washington just like
there are anywhere in any city
regardless of size. But uh this is a
publicity stunt. What makes me so upset
today and I'm smiling because there's
one funny component to it too. the the
cops
plus the National Guard plus the FBI and
ATF and DEA have set up roadblocks on
major thorough affairs like 14th Street
which is one of the most important um
streets in all of Washington. They set
up roadblocks and what are they doing at
the roadblocks? They are writing tickets
for people who are not wearing their
seat belts. Seriously,
>> is that all they're doing?
>> Dozens. That is it. And they they wrote
a couple tickets for uh brake lights
being out. The Washington Post is is
reporting
um there was an incident on uh Ust
Street at 14th and U last night. I was
telling Ted before the show started that
uh that Ust Street is kind of famous
because it was the center of the
Washington jazz scene 100 years ago.
It's where Duke Ellington uh lived and
performed and the Duke Ellington school
is there now. Anyway, it's a real
hipster area. great restaurants and bars
and it's a little bit seedy but in a
cool way. Anyway, a 38-year-old white
man was coming out of a a Subway
sandwich shop. He saw a bunch of
National Guards people and he called
them fascist pigs and words were
exchanged and he threw his sandwich at
one of them and the sandwich hit the
National Guardsman in the shoulder and
he was promptly tackled and arrested and
Janine Piro of course being the new US
attorney for the District of Columbia
called a late night press conference
last night to announce that this
deranged criminal had been arrested. he
was being charged with a felony count of
assaulting a police officer and that her
office would be asking for 10 years in
prison.
Well, you know, it's created it's led to
all these memes being created today. And
I told Ted there's there's no jury
anywhere in Washington that is going to
convict this guy of assault on a police
officer for throwing a sandwich. But
we're we're in the silly period and I I
have to go to the train station. Um is
is well right at 5:30 or 5:25 or
something like that. And I'm going to
have to figure a way around these
roadblocks because my train leaves at
6:05 and I don't have time to fool
around with these people.
>> Well, you better not be You're not
bringing a packed sandwich lunch, are
you? With you on the train because you
could be you could be shot.
>> It's a weapon. It's a It's a weapon.
Yeah. It's gotten just nuts already.
>> I do feel badly for the for the innocent
sandwich that
>> I said to you earlier, I hope it was
either tuna or meatball. At least then
it would be worth it. I hope it's not
like, you know, salami that's not going
to leave a mark.
>> No. Well, not to mention, I love salami.
>> Um, so
well, so yeah, I liked Janine Piro's
statement. She said, "Oh, he thought it
was funny, but we charged him with 10
years in prison. Now he doesn't think
it's so funny." Oh, Janine, you just
made it funnier.
>> Yeah,
>> it was always going to be funny. It's
not going to ever not be funny.
>> This is up there.
>> I made a mistake last week.
>> This is the This is like when uh that
guy the the Iraqi journalist threw the
shoe at Bush.
>> Shoe. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Two shoes.
>> You were saying I
>> I made a mistake last week when I said
that uh the National Guard could only be
called out for three days before
Congress had to approve it. Turns out
there's a proviso in the law that says
that if Congress is not in session, the
three days becomes 30 days. So by the
time the 30 days is up, Congress will be
back in session and then Trump can make
his case for renewing for another 30
days. The bottom line here on this
deployment, I guess we have to call it a
deployment, is Donald Trump hates
looking out the window and seeing
homeless people, right? He hates it and
he wants them all cleared out and he
doesn't care where they go. can put him
in the woods or send him to Maryland or
send him to New York, but he does not
want homeless people in the the parts of
Washington where tourists go, which is
sick. But, you know, rather than to try
to fix the the homeless problem, you
just throw them out and make them
somebody else's problem. That's what
we're headed toward.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I mean that's a very
different attitude than look, he wasn't
my favorite president, but George HW
Bush wrote quite eloquently about
looking out the window of the White
House and seeing a homeless guy sleeping
on a great uh in the ellipse or near the
ellipse uh between the White House and I
don't know what street that is. Um you
would know and he and he just said this
is just not right. This is this is
beneath the dignity of of the United
States of America. And of course,
obviously he was right. But there's been
no I I don't think there's ever been a
serious attempt to to grapple with
homelessness at the federal level. Um
there's a couple of cities who do a good
job. They call it housing first like in
Dallas and Denver. And basically it's
conditionfree housing.
>> Just come in. If you have a substance or
an alcohol abuse problem, no worries.
You can keep using come in and of course
obviously we're going to have counselors
help you and social workers help you.
Just having a home, just having a roof
over your head often goes a long way to
making people stop self-medicating.
>> That's right. That's exactly right. And
I I want to point out real quickly, too,
that Robbie is informing me that
Sandwich Man has also been fired from
his job.
>> Oh yeah, he was a DOJ employee. Yeah.
>> A DOJ employ. Oh my god. The the world's
gone crazy or we've gone crazy anyway.
>> Yeah. I mean, what I mean, what does it
mean, right? I mean, so the fact that
first of all, a heavily armed guy with
Kevlar is so pissed that he gets a
sandwich thrown at him that he has to go
after him. Okay. And then what does it
mean? What is what message, you know,
uh, politically is the administration
trying to send with such a radical
overcharge? I mean, you know, obviously
they know that people like us are going
to make fun of them and everyone else is
going to make fun of them and the
overcharge is only going to draw
attention to it. Yes. Are they basically
just like is it is this simply like a
don't [__] with us move or
>> That's exactly what it is.
>> That's exactly what it is. And like I
said, if if these guys were going to go
to, you know, deep southeast Washington,
which is the highest crime or deep
northeast Washington as well, the the
two highest crime areas in the city, and
try to straighten the the place out and,
you know, maybe raid the crackouses or,
you know, disrupt shootings or whatever.
Okay, great. Good on them.
>> That's not what they're doing.
>> No, not at all.
>> I think this is all about normalizing
the militarization of American city
streets. Um, you know, the thing the LA
and the DC I mean they're basically
standing around. They're not really
doing anything like you say. So, what's
this? This is about making us used to
seeing heavily armed soldiers on the
street. The way that if you live in
Israel, you're always used to seeing
soldiers with uh you know uzies uh out
on the street. Uh if you live in if
you're in any number of countries in the
developing world, you're used to seeing
heavily armed troops or paramilitaries
out on the streets. And you know, I
think that's about that's what this is
about.
>> I think that's exactly right.
>> Yeah. Um, let's talk about uh we got to
talk about the big story of the day
because we time is short. I don't want
to miss out on it. Uh, Putin and Trump
meeting today in Anchorage, Alaska. Um,
Nicholas Kristoff at the New York Times
had I thought and he's not he's normally
one of the more sober Democrats. I
thought he had a complete case of
Russian derangement syndrome today. He
said that the choice of Anchorage,
Alaska was a uh a sop to Putin because
it used to belong to Russia and it
confirms the idea that borders are
funible.
Now, I could I could interpret it the
opposite and say, well, it's actually a
diss to Putin because we're forcing him
to come to us and also he doesn't get
like a 16, you know, a 21 gun salute at
the White House and he doesn't get uh,
you know, and also we're rubbing his
nose in the fact that we now own former
Russian property. I mean, which I don't
think that's true either, but I mean,
it's just basically looking for stuff to
criticize. I think they chose Anchorage
because it's sort of halfway in between.
>> Right. Right. It's going to take Trump
probably what seven hours, seven and a
half hours to get there. It's going to
take Putin maybe 10 hours to get there.
Little less than that. Go.
>> It's either that or Vladivastto. Right.
>> Well, I think you're right. I I think
Yeah, that's right. It's either that or
Vladivastic. Um Vladivastic. Uh I think
you're right. I think it's kind of sort
of the halfway point. Yeah, that
>> I'm sure that's what I'm sure that's
what
>> I will say today, I was looking at the
Russian media today, the Russians are
bringing a who's who of their top
diplomats and negotiators. So, at least
from the Russian side, they're taking
this very seriously.
Ah, sanctions temporary lifted. Could RT
and Sputnik be back on the menu? That is
the subject of hours and hours of text
messages I have been exchanging all day
with my former Sputnik and RT um
colleagues. There are a lot of hopeful
people who were not hopeful yesterday.
So that's
>> I'm sure
>> that's what we're pulling for.
>> Obviously there's not going to be any
deal without without that happening. I
would think
>> it's one of those things like I don't
think it's a priority. I don't think
it's the a priority but I think it
doesn't nothing gets done without that
happening.
>> If that makes sense. Yes, indeed.
>> So, uh, basically it looks like this is
all going to boil down to mineral
rights, right? So, Zalinski promised
rare earth meta, uh, minerals to, uh,
Trump if he kept supporting Ukraine. Um,
now Putin's like, I'll see your rare
earths and I'll raise you 2 million tons
of aluminum that you really need. Um,
and so basically,
is this is it going to boil down to an
eBay auction for uh whoever is willing
to cough up the most minerals to Trump?
>> I think so, Ted. Uh, but at the same
time, they're going to have to throw
something at Zalinski.
You know, you gota you got to get
Zalinski to a place where he's willing
to concede territory. That's the bottom
line.
>> He's going to have to concede territory,
>> right? I mean, he's saying, "Yeah, I
mean, well, he is going to have to,"
right? I mean, so I think I mean, what
this looks like to me, if it works,
John, and tell me what if you if you
think I'm wrong, is basically, uh, Trump
and Putin hash out a deal. Crimea
obviously stays with Russia. Donbas
pretty much stays with Russia. Uh, the
probably uh, no NATO membership for
Ukraine, which makes sense because
they'd have a disputed border anyway.
Zilinsky can stay because his own people
will get rid of him and send him off to
to Lake Ko. So, uh they can join the EU,
no mus, no fuss. Um and then basically
that's and then they go to they go to
then Trump calls Zilinsky and says,
"This is it. Take it or leave it. I'll
offer you security guarantees if you
agree to it, but not if you don't agree
to it. Um and then I'll just stop. I'll
just cut off all funding and arms.
That's it.
>> You know,
>> that's what it basically looks like.
>> I think so. And and so many people have
been saying for so long that Zalinski is
weak. Zalinski is in a box. He's in a
corner. He can't call the shots. He's he
actually has a couple of cards in this
hand.
>> Well, he can just say no. and he can
bring the Germans and the French and and
the rest of the of the European
countries, whether they're NATO or the
EU, along with him and try to isolate uh
Trump and without without a formal
agreement seating this this territory
there there is no peace and then Trump
fails.
>> No doubt. No doubt.
>> Can I ask can I add something? Um Eric
Huso is saying what about the Ukraine
Nazis? Um, Colonel uh uh
uh Doug um Oh my god, what's the matter
with me?
You know who I'm talking about. Doug uh
now I have to look at my phone.
McGregor. Colonel Doug McGregor was on
Judge Npalitano today and Npalitano
asked him what about the Ukrainian Nazis
or these Nazi units? He said um they
were decimated early early in the
fighting. They've been moved far away
from the front. They're less
>> right. They got captured.
>> That's right. And they're just not
um they're not of import. So the
Ukrainians have essentially already be
been denazified is what he said. And and
he's kind of pro-Russian. So I mean
>> I mean look, I always said that
denoxific we you and I both said that
denazification was always a throwaway
demand.
>> Yeah, it was. We we have said that
>> and and it kind of it kind of had to be
because it's impossible to enforce. I
mean, yeah, you know, you want to see
all those Bandaraa signs ripped off the
wall, but that's for the Ukrainians to
deal with.
>> That's it.
>> That's right.
>> So, all right. So, I guess uh we need a
uh Oh, this is really funny. After this
meeting, we need an emergency drogram
live stream this weekend,
>> perhaps. So, we'll see how it goes.
>> We'll see how it goes. John and I are
going to be in the same city this
weekend. Yes.
>> So, we'll be both be here in whatever is
left in New York after it all boils away
in the current heat wave. Um, so let's
see. Uh, did you get a chance to go to
Russia when we all were implied with
Sputnik? No, I never went. And I kind of
always fished around for an invitation,
but
>> I always fished for
>> I went um I I went on my own dime uh in
uh 2023
and uh it was great. I mean, yeah, I
mean I'd been before, but it was
obviously really interesting to go in
the current situation
>> uh after the beginning of the war. the
biggest uh there were some serious
practical concerns which is uh even
though things were a lot cheaper for
tourists than they had been uh you had
to bring all of your money in cash
because your credit cards and your debit
cards don't work at all. So um although
I found a workaround, but I'm not going
to say what that was because it might
screw things up for uh other tourists
who go there. But there there is a
workaround.
>> Uh you know I hope I I I don't know if
it still might not work anymore but who
knows. Uh, Asaf had never had more than
200 people. Cameron Drawley says, "It's
weird, but it's been blown way out of
proportion in my opinion."
>> I think that's probably right.
>> Perhaps, but I mean, you know, how many
how many American military units have
swas on their uniforms? I mean, not that
many. Uh, none. You know, like you can
be drummed out of the military for being
a neo-Nazi.
>> You know, there you might get promoted.
>> Um, so yeah. No, we're I'm very hopeful.
We'll see what happens. Although,
frankly, I'm I'm hopeful for this show,
too. I mean, you know, it's
>> I am too. I am, too. And, you know,
we're getting to the point, thanks to
our fantastic and dedicated uh listeners
and viewers, that um
we're getting to the point where we may
not need a helping hand from RT or from
uh from
>> That's true. Especially if you all go to
over to Rumble uh Rumble.com. Yeah,
>> there's the terrible URL. We didn't
invent it. The C thing. Just go to
Rumble if you're not already doing that.
We get paid like 80 times more uh if you
literally if you go watch us on Rumble.
Uh and also there's going to be
exclusive content over there. It's you
could just you can either see all Rumble
content exclusively for five bucks for
10 bucks a month. But if you don't care
about Rumble in general, you just want
to see us, it's five bucks a month or if
you just watch us over there, um it's
it's helpful, too. So that's that's our
little that's our little sales pitch
here. Um, okay. So, let's move on here.
So, what do you So, what do you what do
you expect from this initial meeting?
Some people are reporting this is a
getting to know you summit and that the
real thing will be later.
>> Yeah, they're trying to tamp down
expectations, but you know how Trump is.
Trump is going to probably throw out
this gigantic grand plan to end all
conflicts. Just
>> I like it.
>> Yeah, I do too. just to see what uh what
the Russians uh response will be. Um
there there's never any downside to
diplomacy. I I've said this for decades.
>> It's never a bad thing to talk to our
enemies.
>> Never.
>> Better to jaw jaw than to war. Churchill
said,
>> "Yeah, that's right. We we shouldn't
expect any giant breakthroughs, but this
is at the opening of a door and I
>> happen. So, is is Putin the reticence
madman that's being portrayed in the
American media?
>> Nope.
Not if he's bringing Lavrov and a and a
and a stable of seasoned diplomats. No.
>> And his own self.
>> Seriously. And his own self. That's
right. This is a summit. An actual
summit.
>> No, this is this is too serious. This is
a serious thing. Um
>> Yeah. I mean, who knows? I mean, I think
it's in a way, I don't think this is
complicated. Um, you know, it's like the
details of land swaps will the drawing
that border will look like Versailles in
1919. But
>> yes,
>> um, and definitely it's going to be an
ugly look for the Ukrainians as their
fate is decided
>> uh whether they get to stay in their
hometown or not
>> uh based on the whims of cgraphers. So
it is going to feel a little bit like
British imperialism but
>> um okay Israel uh lots going on there.
So uh basically Israel's now talking to
five countries about uh accepting Gazin
refugees, expulsion victims, ethnic
cleansing victims. Um is this going to
go anywhere, John? I mean I I
>> No, I talked to Miko Pellet about this
today uh for my other podcast. This is
this is literally the definition of
ethnic cleansing. Yes.
>> Which is a form of genocide and is
illegal under international law. So no,
they they tried with the Albanians. They
tried with the Indonesians. They tried
with the Egyptians and the Saudis. Now
they're talking about sending two
million people to South Sudan, the worst
place on earth.
>> Ridiculous.
>> You can't do it. It's illegal. I
strongly recommend um that people read
the latest Ezra Klene um transcript
that's in the New York Times where he
interviewed a guy who's an expert on the
definition of genocide which is called
is it genocide? And basically it just
explains the history of how genocide
came to be defined as a term uh during
actually before World War II uh and then
and then how it got popularized.
>> Do you know where it came from?
>> Isn't isn't it from the Armenian
genocide or
>> No.
>> No. Um, it was it was a word coined by
the father of Robert Morganthal
in 1921.
He happened to be on an American ship in
the port of Isizmir
as the Turks were slaughtering Greeks
and Armenians, literally slaughtering
them.
>> And
Yenos is peoples, right?
>> Yenosidi genocide is the killing of a
people. And so he coined the term in a
letter that he was writing to the
president.
Yeah. In fact, Robert Morgan thou he was
almost like a hundred years old. He came
to testify before the Senate rel foreign
relations committee when I was working
there and he had to take my arm in the
hall and I walked him to the hearing
room and I said that I had just finished
a book called um Smeirna 1921. I said I
didn't realize that your father had
coined the term genocide. and he said
yes. And on his deathbed he said that
that was the thing that he was the most
proud of.
>> That's cool. I like it.
>> Isn't that cool?
>> Um so and yeah, the definition of
genocide is not just you know uh death
camps like Achvitz. It's u you know it
can include that of course but it's also
about uh making it impossible for people
to live in a certain place. You you
might not that you could have a genocide
that might not kill anyone.
>> That's right. Like forcing them to move
to South Sudan. And Eric has a question
here too. odds that Israel tax Iran
again. Eric, I have moved dramatically
over the past week, especially after
reading Treata Parsey's uh piece on
Substack a couple of days ago. I think
the chances are very good that Israel is
going to attack Iran in the next three
weeks. It'll be
>> for distraction purposes to uh scuttle
any peace talks to uh force Trump to to
come to heal.
>> Exactly. Uhhuh.
>> Will it work? I mean, if you're if
you're if you're Trump, you've got to be
like you gota you gota see right through
that.
>> I mean, that's the kind of thing that
Trump would do. Therefore, I would think
that Trump would recognize it.
>> I think I think he probably would.
>> It's Yeah. You know what I mean? It's
like,
>> yeah,
>> don't [__] a bullshitter.
>> That's right. I hope that's the case.
I'm worried
>> also. So, okay. So, these five countries
would all be viewed as complicit in
genocide. So,
>> they're just Why are they talking to the
Israelis at all? Ted, a lot of them
haven't actually been asked. Like the
Indonesians are like, "Whoa, whoa, we
never heard of it."
>> Yeah. We're not giving up an island for
two million Palestinians to come. No.
And the Albanians are like, "Are you
kidding us? We're the poorest country in
Europe, and you want to send two million
more people here?"
That's insane. Well, I'm sure they would
love to divvy them up. Kind of like uh
you know, the US divvied up the
Guantanamo victims. Um but, you know,
there were only a few hundred of those.
>> Yeah. And some got lucky and some got
unlucky. Some went to Switzerland, some
went to Albania,
>> right? Yeah. Some went to Bermuda,
>> some went to Tahiti. Yeah. A couple more
went to, you know, Bangladesh. So, it's
the luck of the draw.
>> Uh I uh let's Okay. Well, we got to talk
about this uh Sue me Terry story. Uh
this is your wheelhouse. This is your
bailwick. John, take it away.
>> Oh, okay. And I have one minute because
I gotta go. Sumi Terry, who I had
forgotten until Robbie reminded us is
the wife of Max Boot and she is now
>> formerly of the Wall Street Journal.
>> That's right. So, I'm going to I'm going
to get the exact
>> He was my editor at the Wall Street
Journal for a time.
>> She's a She's a big deal. So, she's
being charged with spying spying for
South Korea. This is going to be a real
stretch, it seems to me, Ted, because
she's widely respected, providing
analysis. The Justice Department is
saying that actually, I'm going to pull
it up. She was she's been charged with
multiple offenses not under the
Espionage Act, but under the Farah Act,
Foreign Agents Registration Act, which
means that oh my god, she forgot to fill
out a form on the internet. That makes
it a felony. Now, that calls for a
sentence of 0 to six months, first
offense.
On Farah, the Justice Department doesn't
care what it is. Uh, Maria, what's her
face? From from Russia. Thank you. Uh,
was convicted of failing to file and
even though it was zero to six months
recommendation, she got 18 months in
solitary confinement. So, I don't know
why the CIA is demanding that these
charges be pursued. I think it's kind of
nuts. And I'm no friend of Max Boots. I
never never
>> Do you think she's guilty?
She may be guilty of, you know,
laziness. And like I say, the crime
literally is failing to fill out a form
on the internet. Literally,
>> that's that's sort of like uh Yeah.
Like, you know, we talked about RT and
Sputnik.
>> That's something that like under um
under the uh what is that thing called?
The Farah. Like they had to fill out a
form every single day. Yeah.
>> And I'm going to apologize to our
viewers. I've got to run. I have to
dodge these these roadblocks and get to
the train station.
>> John, go ahead. Go, go with God. I'll
see you this weekend.
>> I'll see you tomorrow at the You Know
Where and uh see you at the You Know
Where. I'll be there.
>> And All right. Cool. And and we'll be
back uh tomorrow at 5:00 PM, right?
You're still good for tomorrow at 5.
>> Okay, cool. I'm gonna Thanks, John. Go.
John's going to take off. Um I'm going
to stick around. There was a request uh
from inside the uh inside the chat here
on both the Rumble and on uh the uh on
YouTube to uh do a Q&A with me once John
leaves. So, if anybody's interested uh
in doing that, I'll stick around as long
as people are interested in doing that.
Okay. All right. Um Okay. First, uh
Clovis overrules us all. Clovis is my
cat, so uh if he blesses us with his
presence, I'm looking around. I don't
see him. Okay. So, uh, I'm being
requested here for the, uh, to for the
LA Times story debacle. All right, I
will tell that story as short and as
sweet as I possibly can because it is a
very, uh, long and complicated ordeal,
but the long story short is in uh, 2009,
I was hired as the staff cartoist at the
LA Times. Um, it was honestly, you know,
just like one of the biggest breaks you
could ever get, especially at a time
when the industry was falling apart.
2009 uh you know was during the global
recession and newspapers were hit super
hard. So I was really lucky to get the
gig. I was very excited about it and uh
anyway I worked there without incident
uh between 2009 and 2015.
Now, um that what that entailed was
every every 2 three days I drew a
cartoon for the LA Times. And then about
this is important. Um about 2012 or so,
they called me and said, "Oh, would you
be willing to write a blog that would go
with the cartoon that would sort of uh
explain uh you sort of how you came up
with your cartoon, maybe the background
of the topic or whatnot." And I said,
"Sure." You know, they were like, "We'll
pay you a little more money." Um, and I
was like, fine. So, anyway, every my
routine was like every single every
every single week I would send my editor
uh a couple of ideas. She would choose
one um and then I would draw it and I
would draw I would write up a blog and
they would publish it and that was it.
And uh I went to visit a few times. Um,
I also went to Afghanistan for the LA
Times. Um, and did uh comics journalism
from there in 2010. Uh, part of that
ended up in my book, After We Kill You,
We Will Welcome You as Honored Guests.
But it was a great relationship. I want
to be very clear here. There was never
any tension or friction whatsoever. I
got along great with all of my editors.
Uh I basically dealt with three editors
um on the except when one editor would
Nick Goldberg who was the Uber editor
would call you know every now and then
just when all the other three were out
and he would take care of it. So, uh,
see, so anyway, uh, unbeknownst to me,
in 2014,
the LAPD pension fund purchased
controlling interest in a company called
Trunk, which was also known as Tribune
Publishing, which was the parent company
of the LA Times in and 14 other
newspapers, including the Chicago
Tribune and the Baltimore Sun. uh the
Orlando Sentinel, I forget all the the
whole long list, but I didn't know about
any of this. But the uh LA the LAPD told
the LA Times, "We're really pissed at
Ted R." Because he every now and then he
draws cartoons that make fun of the
police chief, Charlie Beck, and make fun
of the LAPD. Um but nobody ever told me,
"Cut it out. Stop. Leave the LAPD
alone." If they had, I could be honest,
I'm not like John. I probably would have
said like, okay, uh there's lots of
other stuff to draw about. I mean,
there's always guy there's always limits
in in in journalism. You know, you I'm
sure you don't you wouldn't be smart to
criticize Jeff Bezos if you were at the
Washington Post. So, I uh you know, but
I just out of ignorance just kept doing
my thing. And every now and then I did
cartoons against the LAPD, which is the
nation's, you know, most militarized
police force and you know, guilty of a
lot of violence obviously. So anyway, um
the summer of 2014 of 2015 rolls around.
I'm at a u I'm with my kid at a county
fair riding a ferris wheel. It's 8:00 at
night. I get a call, East Coast time. I
get a call from Nick Goldberg uh at from
the uh from the uh LA Times and he says,
"Ted, what's going on?" And I'm like,
"Nick, I don't know what you're talking
about." And he's like, "Well, uh, you
know, the LAPD
is questioning, you know, an account of
of a of an incident that occurred in
2001." What he was talking about was a
cartoon that had run many months before
that was basically about how the LAPD
was going against jaywalking. Um, and I
said, I wrote a blog that went with it.
And, uh, I said, you know, this time
it's personal. Back in 2001, I was on
Bill Maher's show uh politically
incorrect. I was walking in West
Hollywood from ABC television CBS
television city up to Melrose Boulevard
to have dinner with some friends. Um I
was crossing the street. Um by the way,
in the crosswalk with the green light
with the little walking guy and a
motorcycle cop arrested me, handcuffed
me, roughed me up, wrote me a cit a
misdemeanor citation for jaywalking.
Obviously, the guy had a uh you know, he
had a uh a quot to fill. Um I was
furious about this because I hadn't done
anything wrong. There was a angry crowd
uh you know, yelling at the cop. And
there was quite a scene going on. And
finally, ultimately a uh you know, his
partner showed up on a motorcycle and
told him, you know, what the [__] are
you doing? Let's get out of here. And so
then he unccuffed me and gave me the
ticket, threw my driver's license into
the gutter and drove off. So I filed a
formal complaint with internal affairs.
Nothing ever came of it. Never heard
from them. Um, and I forgot all about
it. But I did write about this to when I
read about the jaywalking crackdown to
just say how stupid, you know, as a New
Yorker, you know, jaywalking is not
enforced here. And it was just one of
these things about like how do I um, you
know, how can they do this? and this is
what happened to me. If it can happen to
me, it can happen to you. Blah blah
blah. Anyway, the LAPD went into their
old files, dug up my old complaint, uh,
and with internal affairs, and they
called the LAPD, and they said, "We
secretly audio taped back in 2001 Ted
R's interaction with the police officer
um, who who uh who arrested him and
handcuffed him. But we're going to and
but he was never handcuffed. The cop was
always polite. He was never roughed up.
There was never a crowd of angry angry
people. Ted Raw made the whole thing up.
So under basically what they were
accusing me of and what the LA Times
agreed that I had done was that I had
lied in print. So this wasn't true. Of
course I I remembered it very vividly
and I knew what had happened, but
there's no way to prove a negative,
right? So I the the investigative
reporter for the LA Times, a guy named
Paul Pringle, who has since
characterized himself as a voice of
reason in the uh in the uh in in
Southern California journalism and even
wrote a book, pretty wellreceived a few
years ago about it. Calls me up and he's
like, "Listen, uh can I I'm going to
send you the recording the recording of
this interaction and it proves that what
you said happened didn't happen." So he
sends it to me. It's about six six and a
half minutes long. You can find it on
the internet. I posted it on the
internet. And all you can hear is
static. It's literally like
and you can hear that there might be
some voices in the background, but you
can't recognize them. I couldn't even
recognize my own voice. You really can't
hear anything. And and Paul Pringle
goes, "See, there's no sound of
handcuffs going on. There's no there's
there's no sound of an angry crowd.
There's no indication that the cop ever
was rude to you. And I'm like, this
thing doesn't show anything. It could
have space aliens on it. But he didn't,
you know, the guy the fix was clearly
in. Long story short, Nick Goldberg
fires me. Um, they print an article in
the LA Times calling me a liar and a
fabulist to explain my firing. And
clearly the goal here was to not only
get rid of me but also to make sure I
would never work in journalism again.
Few days later I start getting I I get a
a fan who writes to me and says you know
I've been reading about this. This is a
big national story. It's on Fox News.
It's on the AP. It's all over the place.
Um and uh you know Ted R fired for for
making up story about poor innocent
LAPD. So uh I'm completely desperate.
But I think my life and my career is
completely destroyed. And anyway, this
fan writes and says, "Have you ever
heard of audio enhancement technology?"
And audio enhancement is basically uh
where you can strip away noise and maybe
reveal what's underneath the noise. So,
can you please send So, this guy was
like, I know a guy who knows a guy. Long
story short, three different people did
enhancements and they all ended up
getting the same results, which was once
you cleared away the noise, it was still
pretty crappy, but you could hear, among
other things, uh, people screaming at
the police officer, let him go, why are
you hurting him, take off his handcuffs,
and so on. It all vindicated my sto my
side of the story. Nothing vindicated
the LAPD side of the story. I sent this
audio recording to the LA Times figuring
it's going to be fine. They're gonna
they're going to see reason. Obviously,
there's no reason for them to go on. But
what I didn't realize was that there was
this power dynamic where LAPD uh chief
Charlie Beck had secretly met with
Austin Bututner, who was a former
mayoral candidate. Uh he was a a hedge
fund billionaire, the publisher of the
LA Times who had been installed by the
LAPD pension fund as publisher in 2014.
They even gave him as soon as he in the
same way that Obama won the Nobel uh in
uh for peace prize six months after
being president just basically for being
a Democrat and for being black. Um,
Austin Butner won the LAPD badge and
eagle award for service to the LAPD just
for being the publisher of the LA Times.
Parenthetically, you're not you're not
supposed to as an employee of the LA
Times accept any kind of awards
whatsoever from uh any agency other
than, you know, something like the
Pulitzers, a journalistic organization,
which obviously the LAPD is not. You're
certainly not supposed to accept favors
from the government. Anyway,
long story short, I post all this um to
my to my blog. I write about it in my
syndicated column. Uh a news website
called a new domain goes after it, sicks
their investigative team all over it. Um
it ultimately works it winds its way
through the Guardian. Uh the New York
Observer, owned by Jared Kushner at the
time, decides to do their own
enhancement. Everyone ends up basically
on my side and against the LAPD, the LA
Times. The LA Times three weeks later
decides to double down with yet another
smear piece saying, "Well, okay, this
time we hired our own enhancement people
and they say that Ted R's stuff isn't
there." Well, first of all, there's no
Ted R stuff. this is other people
professionals who found this information
and then um they so my friend who's at a
new domain she's like you know I went to
school with this guy uh this audio
enhancement expert that the LA Times is
citing it doesn't sound like he would
say something like this that he would
make things up she calls him up she
calls me back two hours later she said
you better be sitting down I just got
off the phone with Paul with uh with uh
Paul Griggas I think was his name. Uh,
and he says, you know, the LA the LA
Times never hired me. They lied about
me. They made up a quote to say that I
had said there was nothing there. I
never wrote any said anything of the
kind. The LA Times basically just made
this up and used my name. And now my
reputation is smeared because everyone
thinks that I'm the stoogge of the LA
Times and the LAPD. LA Times is in
embroiled in this massive scandal in the
in August of September of 2015. Um,
after a while they had to shut down all
of the comment sections to the uh to the
LA Times website because even in the
sports section, people were posting
comments like, "Yeah, you say the
Packers won, but what does the LAPD say
happened at the game?" So, anyway, this
went on for years. I sued in uh LA in
the LA uh trial court. Um the fix was in
um every single step of the way. Uh, and
I kind of feel bad because there's
questions piling up here and I can go on
and talk about the court procedure, but
basically uh this story involves
everyone from Governor uh Gavin Newsome
to uh the uh to Tom Gerardi, the
disgraced uh lawyer who was married to
uh Real Housewives of Beverly Hills,
Erica Jane, to uh my judge who was
having an affair with Tom Gerardy who
was also friends with Charlie Beck.
It's an incestuous snake bit politically
over there. Anyway, that's the short
version of what happened. Needless to
say, ultimately Gavin Newsome overruled
the uh California Supreme Court, had my
case thrown out. Uh and that's kind of
like where that went down five years
later. I currently have a judgment for
$1.2 2 million in legal fees against me
in the state of California because
basically the court decided, you know,
they decided to award the LA Times
uh their legal fees because they are the
poor innocent victims of Ted R who was
trying to censor them. Okay. What was my
beef? Uh Reed wants to know what was my
beef with Anne Coulter. and Coulter
jokingly, haha, said, "Hey,
um, you know, Ted Ra, uh, entered the,
uh, the anti-semitic Iranian cartoon
contest."
Okay, I didn't. So, I was really furious
about this and I did threaten to sue
her. I put it out. I I asked people, "If
I sue her, would you help fi back me up
financially?" Uh, I collected a lot of
pledges, but then when I talked to
lawyers, they said, "I'd never win.
She's protected by First Amendment and
satire just as I am." And, uh, I guess I
guess unless I'm going after the LAPD.
And so therefore, uh, I decided not to
pursue it, as I said, in public. Um, and
I I think it was really reckless. Uh,
she basically accused me of consorting
with terrorists and being an
anti-semite. So, I was really really
furious here. Okay. Um,
Starline wants to know, "How do I feel
about Ian Ran?" Two-part question.
First, as an author, second, as a
leerous old woman who prayed on young
male college libertarians. Um, I'm not a
fan of her writing. I I I definitely
understand the appeal to the people who
she appeals to. Um, I think she's
talented. Uh, but she's not my cup of
tea at all. Um, as someone who's always
kind of had a fondness for older women,
uh, I don't think that those uh, young
male college libertarians were
victimized in any way, shape, or form,
when I was, uh, you know, they were over
18 years old. They're consenting adults,
and she probably taught them a lot, and
uh, you know, good for them. Uh, but if
they're under 18, then I feel very
differently about it. I mean, when I was
20, I had a uh, over 60 girlfriend for a
time, so I'm biased there. Okay, let me
uh we've got a few more questions here.
Okay, not um over on the Rumble feed, uh
Nadia Margaret wants to know, "Do I draw
by hand or do I use a graphic tablet?"
Draw by hand. Um here's a cartoon that
I'm working on right now. This is how I
draw them like a pen and ink. Uh it's
just on Bristol board. Here's the pen. I
draw it black and white like this. And
then uh when it's done, I scan it into
Photoshop and add the colors and make
any mistakes that uh fixed in Photoshop.
Um, okay. How do I get in uh Rex0527 on
Rumble wants to know, "How do I get into
politics? I'm 16 in Arkansas and I
really want to be more involved in
anything. Helps also to love your
content. I've been watching you since
you guys started." Thank you so much,
Rex. Much appreciated. Um, so how do you
want to be more involved? Well, I mean,
it depends on, you know, if you want to
be involved in one of the two major
parties, the best thing to do is is to
go to the lo local party headquarters or
the part party headquarters of one of
the candidates. Um, and, you know, get
to volunteer for a campaign and work for
it. If you're more interested in
activist politics outside of electoral
politics, uh, find an organization that
speaks to you and just reach out and
say, "Hey, what are you guys doing? Do
you have any meetings? Uh, can I, uh, do
you have any literature I can read?" Uh,
that's what I did when I was a kid. Um,
I I went to work I was 10 years old and
I worked for the McGovern campaign with
my mom. Oh, I didn't reach out. She did
that. Uh, but I did phone bank for uh
Jimmy Carter. And then I moved to the
left after Michael Dakus. I worked on I
was a New York youth coordinator for
Dakus when I was 25 in 1988. And I
decided that I really just couldn't
stand electoral Democratic politics
internally anymore and that I was to the
left of that and uh I migrated. But, you
know, you do you and just basically keep
an eye out for people who appeal to you
that way. Um, so many questions. Okay.
Uh, Hardin66
wants to know, "Do you have any concerns
about how the media is currently used
within the US? As from the outside, it
looks like it's all propaganda for
political gain as opposed to informing
the public." Um, well, yeah. Um, you
know, I do we have 10 hours? Uh we're
we're not going to be able to get to all
that but yes um the obviously so much of
the media is propaganda and it's very
dangerous. It literally leads to people
dying in wars. I mean think about the uh
you know currently what's going on in
Israel. US support for Israel is uh
without any fil any filter at all. Uh
there's no restraint whatsoever and as a
result hundreds of thousands and it is
hundreds of thousands of Palestinians
have lost their lives. Many more have
been severely traumatized. They're going
to ethnically cleanse the entire strip
if they get away with it. And they're
doing that because of the media uh not
only in Israel, which is strictly
controlled and self-controlled, but also
here in the United States because we're
paying the bill. And we're only paying
the bill because the political support
is generated by American propaganda. So,
yeah, no doubt about it. It's a
terrible, terrible thing. Um, all right.
So, let's talk about what's my opinion
on georgism and taxing the unimproved
value of land. I need more details on
that, Tom. I I have to admit no opinion
at all. Um, was the 2001 jaywalking
before or after 911? Good question. Uh,
Star Lion. Uh, it was um a it was
actually after 911. Um, it was in uh
when was this? This was uh it was
literally I think 3 weeks after 9/11. I
think it was something like se like uh
October 4th or so 2001. And in fact, one
of the things that the people in the
crowd yelled at the cop was uh you know
what's wrong with you? Don't you have
anything better to do with everything
that's going on? And that was a
reference to 911. Um you know it this
this uh it was the corruption in uh what
was called the west traffic bureau was
thick and thin. In fact a group of
dissident LAPD officers were furious at
being told that they had to write
tickets even to people who had not done
anything wrong because they were just
trying to generate revenue for the city.
Uh and they had sued at the same time.
Now in the same so those people the
dissident cops they were being passed
over for promotion and denied raises all
the time. Meanwhile my cop will Durr uh
was viewed as was constantly being
promoted and told that and uh being
given great reviews because he was a
corrupt police officer. Um okay let's
talk about another wonderful secret
wants to know Trump's been out on bail
since August 2023. 200 grand in his
active Georgia criminal case. looks like
he'll be held accountable after his
term. That case isn't gonna just
magically disappear. Very true. Very,
very true. Um,
in my experience, who which side has
more grifters and hypocrites? Reed wants
to know, liberal or conservative media?
Well, I'm biased because I come from the
left, so I pay more attention to the
liberals than to the conservatives. you
know, you always police your own side
more than you police the uh other side,
but I you I pay more attention to the
liberals and the Democrats. And uh you
know, I would have to say there's more
true believers I think on the right than
there are on in mainstream left media.
Uh you know, there's you're not really
getting the whole story. Like most of
the New York Times editorial page,
they're like me. They're socialists, but
they can't admit it. They're just trying
to cash a paycheck. And they'll tell you
like over drinks the real deal, but you
know, they just don't want to do that.
Um, here we go. Star lying in print next
to plagiarism, the fastest way to
destroy a career in publishing. Yes.
Yes. Um, what's my prediction about the
Gaza genocide war going to end? Kak Ka
Punct wants to know, Netanyahu in jail.
Will the UN finally interfere or is the
ethnic cleansing going to continue? It's
really really hard to say, but clearly
the you uh Israel is completely um a
cornered animal increasingly. So um you
know I this is going to go one of two
ways. Either of them is going to be
extreme and Netanyahu could end up in
jail on those domestic political
charges. Um I would love to see him
arrested and brought up uh to the H
where he belongs to be held accountable
for what he's doing and what Israel is
doing in general. Not just him, but all
of the top Israeli commanders and
government uh and min the war the war
ministry uh the war cabinet members
should all be brought up brought up. Um
will the UN finally interfere? I think
that's extremely doubtful just because
the UN doesn't have a great history of
bringing in white helmets to put an end
to genocide. They weren't there for
Rwanda in any meaningful way. I don't
think they're going to be there in any
in any meaningful way. the ethnic
cleansing is going to continue. Uh I
don't think any other country is going
to take them uh the Palestinians and I
don't think they should because that
would be enabling genocide. So I think
that's going to um you know I I I don't
I I don't have an easy prediction there.
I'm really really really sorry. Um, as
someone who has heard recently about
feds in journalism, do you know or how
feds operate in journalism when they il
infiltrate? Well, it's hard to say,
right? I mean, the thing is that to me,
the danger isn't really secret agents in
journalism. To me, the danger is the uh
the chummy relationships that take place
uh in Washington and around the world
where basically, you know, a journalist
makes friends and with politicians and
federal government and federal and state
and local politicians and hangs with
them and likes them. And this is why the
embedding program in the military is so
incredibly toxic. It shouldn't be
permitted at all because it crosses that
line. Journalists should be completely
independent. You shouldn't be able to
have any personal relationship what
whatsoever with the people that you're
covering. I mean, I think that's a big
duh. I think most people would agree
with it. And yet, it happens all the
time. Um, Star Lion is saying, uh,
there's a guy used to work in LAPD
intelligence, Roth Miller, did a few did
a good interview on Gates, the history
of the red squad in the intelligence
division. All right. I'll have to check
that out. Um,
yeah. Uh,
let's see. What's the thing that Oh,
what's the thing I have with Nuome that
makes him look bad? Sarah Lion wants to
know. Okay, I'll I'll fess. So, my case
works its way up to the California
Supreme Court. Um, short. This is uh
right during the pan at the very
beginning of the pandemic uh in 2020 and
they say we are going to rule
unanimously in Ted R's favor. The money
quote is from the initial ruling. This
appears to be one of the most egregious
examples of corruption in the history of
the state of California. My lawyers and
I are completely ecstatic and thrilled
and they say, "But the courts are about
to shut down for months, maybe six
months, maybe a year. The whole country
is going on lockdown. We're all going
away. Uh we'll get back to you." So to
confir to issue the final ruling on
April 1st and I think this is an
interesting choice of date. Suddenly
they without comment after after issuing
this detailed wholesome declamation of
the LAPD and the LA Times and corruption
in Southern California. The court
reverses itself from five to zero to 0
to five against me. No comment in an
uncertified decision like Bush vGore.
That means it's a decision that can
never be used as a precedent in a
California court because they know it's
bad law and because it's political. Um,
and anyway, the very next day I learned
that two things. Number one, all of the
cases against the LA Times have
magically vanished at the California
Supreme Court ruling uh level. Number
two, Gavin Newsome holds a press
conference with Dr. Patsun Xiang, the
new the new owner of the LA Times, um in
LA announcing that he will reopen the
hospitals that he closed in order to
treat California COVID patients.
So, obviously, there was a quid proquo
here. Uh I'll reopen my hospitals if you
get rid of these medalsome people uh
plaintiffs in the various age
discrimination, liel, and other lawsuits
against the LA Times from the previous
regime. You know, Dr. Pat, you could
have called and we could have just
worked it out. I would have settled for
an apology. I didn't need money. I
needed a retraction. But, you know, when
you're when you're a when you're a
hammer, everything looks like a nail.
And that's what Dr. Pat did. So, Gavin
Newsome put his thumb on the scale.
There's no question in my mind at all.
And I think anybody who looks at it
would see the same thing that I saw. And
I swear to God, if he runs for
president, I'm going to make it my
business to make sure that California
journalists go after him and get all the
all the duty, everything there. All
right. So, what's the sat what's the
line between satire and defamation? Um,
well, that's for the courts to decide,
but um, you know, I think I think
defamation is when you say something
that could credibly be construed as true
and is construed as damaging. I mean, so
if I lie about what you wear, that's not
really, you know, it might not be true,
but it doesn't make it defamatory. But a
good example of defamation would be,
let's say context matters. So, let's say
uh you accuse me of not washing my hands
after I go to the bathroom. It's
probably def it's not true or it might
be true, but it's not really defamatory
because who cares if a cartoonist or a
podcaster washes their hands after they
go to the bathroom? But let's say I'm a
butcher. It would completely destroy my
line of work. So in that incident
instance, uh that could be defamatory if
you falsely allege that I don't wash my
hands after I go to the bathroom. Um now
I if I let's say I I do something and
that implies that satirically that a
butcher doesn't wash his hands, but it's
clearly a joke, that's satire. If it's
not clearly a joke, like Anne Coulter,
that's defamation. All right, let's see
what else we got here. Um, and you do
have to So, there's two kinds. You have
to um defamation has to be untrue.
Correct. Um, and you have to prove
damages probably. That's correct, too.
There's two kinds of defamation. There's
p defamation, regular defamation, which
you do have to prove actual damages like
what jobs did you lose? What jobs did
you not get? That's very hard to do.
Then there's defamation per se, which is
a higher standard, but you don't have to
all you have to prove is that it was
said. You don't have to prove that it
would that it cost you any money. That
would be something like, for example,
you accuse someone of being a pedophile
and they are a boy, they are a
scoutmaster. You don't need to prove
actual damages. It's so outrageous and
if it's not true, that that would be
defamation per se in most courts.
I I don't know about I don't know if
George RR Martin will ever finish his
books, but I'm gonna guess probably not.
He's been really slow. Um, all right.
Let's see what else.
Do I think Zachary Beard on Rumble think
the US will ever ratify the Rome Statute
and subject itself to the ICC? No. The
US is a criminal organization and uh
therefore it will never do that. I I
think um how can I send you a copy of my
graphic novel? Do I have a PO box? I do
have a PO uh P po PO box. Um it is on my
website. Go to raw.comcont
and it's right there. Uh so go check
that out. Um
let's see. Uh on which issues do John
and I disagree the most? You know, John
and I tend to agree about a lot of
things. Um, you know, he's he's probably
I'm gonna have to I'm gonna have to
think about that one. I don't really uh
you know, we definitely aren't the same
person and we have different
backgrounds. Um I'm betting that he
might have um a little more affection
for uh you know the the for you know the
the government than I do or but they
betrayed him. I don't know. I'm just I'm
spitting here. It's like I'd like to say
we disagree about a lot of things but I
don't think that's really true. Uh, so
I'm not going to just make that up here.
All right. So, thank you very much, uh,
Marble 455 for that generous donation.
Um, let's see. Can you take your case to
the US Supreme Court? Yes, but so we did
appeal to the US Supreme Court. Um, and
it's a complicated thing. Justice
Clarence Thomas indicated that he was
very interested in my case. And um I'll
take like John, I'll take my my friends
wherever I can find them. The irony is
that when we counted the votes on the
Supreme Court, the liberals were going
to go against me uh because they're in
favor of the anti-slap statute that the
LA Times abused to go after me. Um if
you watch, everybody in the
establishment loves the anti-slap law.
This is the same thing that the New York
Times used to screw over Sarah Palin. Um
anyway, Thomas was interested in taking
the case, but we realized that if we
appe if we got before the US Supreme
Court, and believe me, I would love to
be talking to Nina Totenberg on NPR
about my case, uh it would we would have
lost probably uh by six to three and
then my what the shitty thing that
happened to me would be codified in
federal law and would apply to everyone
in the country. So, it could happen over
and over again. And so one of the things
you don't want to do is make, you know,
if you make bad, they say bad cases make
bad law. They don't mean that the case
involves a bad person. They mean that a
case like mine where it's novel and
strange can lead to a really bad uh
judicial verdict that can end up being
abused by the powers that be. Um, no.
I've never watched The Expanse. Don't
know about it. Uh, who are the good
Democrats in the party right now?
No, there aren't any. Uh, okay. I'll
check out Continuum and Okay, I'm trying
to think. Um,
I think we are probably Okay, Star Lion
saying it's the most Occupy Wall Street
show I've ever seen other than Mr.
Robot. Another great Thinking Man's
show. That's high praise. I will have to
check that out. I've been lately I've
been uh I've been wanting to watch Alien
Earth uh but I don't have the channel
that it's on. I've been watching old
episodes of uh uh God, what's that show
called? Banshee. It's trashy, but kind
of fun. Uh for sure. And Mr. Robot, too.
Yeah, for sure. All right, guys. We are
Oh, we'll do Okay, we'll do one more
here. What do I think of Obama
contacting Mumani a few hours a few days
ago? You know, I'm so happy, Cameron,
that you brought this up because it
really made my blood boil. So, one of
the things that hap, you know, when I
was a kid, um, I got bullied a lot in
elementary school and, uh, sorry, in
junior high school, not in elementary
school as much. And I was walking home
with a guy who lived in my neighborhood
and we were friends and we played
together and like one time he we're
walking back and he had something to
tell me and he's like, "Ted, would you
do me a favor and just not acknowledge
that we're friends at school because,
you know, you're unpopular and no one
likes you. I don't want to be seen as
your friend." So, I had enough pride at
that point to say, "You know what? No, I
don't want to be your friend anymore."
Uh, I you can't be my friend in public.
I don't want to be your friend at all.
Obama calling Mani the other day on the
DL really reminded me of that. Barry,
where the hell is your endorsement?
you know, uh, Zeron Mumdani is the
Democratic nominee for the mayor, mayor
of New York, and he's almost certainly
going to win in the general election,
but he's the Democratic candidate. You
should endorse him no matter what. Um,
and he didn't do that. So, yeah. So,
he's trying to have it both ways, like,
oh, I'm going to be the Eminance Gre.
I'm going to calm him down behind the
scenes and it's going to and blah blah
blah. and it got, you know, leaked out
to the New York Times and other places
and he gave him some some general
advice. You know what? Mandani doesn't
need your advice. I mean, he really
doesn't need anything from Obama. But
what he really needs, if he needs
anything, is his endorsement. Something
that he hasn't gotten from Hakee Jeff or
from Governor Hokll. Um, all the top
Democrats are freezing him out. So,
screw him. Um, I think it's disgusting.
Screw Obama. I hate that. Ah, I love
this story. Okay, Reed, a great
question. What was Barry like at
Colombia? Oh, let me tell my Colombia
story. Okay, I don't know if you've
heard this before, but it's a good
story, so it's worth repeating. So, um,
oh, uh, when I was a sophomore at
Colombia, um, I lived at a dorm called
BHR, Brooks, uh, Brooks, um, what was
something Reed Reed, BHR, uh, anyway,
Huitt, Brooks Hwitt, Reed. And um when I
was uh and so I lived on the first
floor, room 146, Huitt. Uh and kind of
like down the hall, but also on the
first floor uh was the black students
organization. And you know, there
weren't that many black students at
Colombia and they kind of stuck out like
a sore thumb. It was a very very white
school at the time. And I noticed this
one kid who was had a very unusual look
and had a fro uh hanging out a lot. And
uh one time I walked by and I noticed
him being dressed down by the president
of the BSO and I overheard him say and
I'll never forget it. He said, "Barry,
you can't come around here anymore.
You're always coming around here
scamming on girls, but when it comes to
putting up and throwing down and
participating in the struggle, we can
never count on you. You're gonna have to
decide who you are." And uh at this was
at the time when there was the student d
um the the South Africa divestment
struggle at Colombia and other schools
around the country. And basically the
left on campus was focused on that and
the BSO as you can imagine was front and
center there. And so basically, you
know, when he emerged, uh, you know, I
forgot all about Barry Obama until I I
read in uh I guess the early 2000s in
Time or Newsweek that there was this
upand cominging state legislator in
Illinois. And I I'll forget your your
name, but I'll remember your face
forever. And I was like, "Oh my god,
that's the guy I went to school with
back then." I was in the convention hall
in 2004 when he gave his big speech. And
you know, he's a man who's always been
full of [__] Um, when he emerged in
2007 as like, you know, running against
the stupid war in uh in Iraq for the
smart war in Afghanistan, I when, you
know, I I was uh I decided to look into
his voting record. Now, OB Obama voted
six out of six times to fund the war.
Six out of six times. That's when I
realized he was full of [__] Full
disclosure, I voted for John Edwards in
the primaries, even though John Edwards
had already dropped out of the race here
by the time the New York primary
happened in 2008. So, yeah, I saw Obama,
I wouldn't say I mean, you know, define
a lot. He's one of those people that,
you know, you just see sometimes. Um,
and he was a very striking dude. So,
yeah. I mean, I I don't know how many
times I saw him. I guess that's a lot if
you can't really count it. Um so yeah
that yeah Barry Barry never changed MA
that's that's that's really right. Who
have I voted for in the last elections?
Uh last year election uh I voted for uh
Green Party Dr. Jill Stein in the last
election. I voted for um Howie Hawkins
in the um in the 2020 race. I vote voted
for Dr. Stein in 2016 as well. And I
think it was if Ralph Nater was running
in 2012 I think he was. I think I voted
for him. I think that's exactly right.
Um, okay. So, there we go. Um, okay. Oh,
wait. All right. There's more. Yellow
Banana wants to know if we could go back
to 2008, would you change any
presidential results between the two
candidates? All right. So, this was uh
John McCain versus Barack Obama.
Well, I mean, yeah. Well, between the
two candidates, you know, it's a good
question. I mean, I hated John McCain.
He was a wararmonger. um a representable
figure. I was really truly terrified of
what would happen if Sarah Palin became
president. Um you know, and I thought
John McCain was like five seconds away
from dropping dead. So um you know, I
guess I'm agnostic about that. I I think
in the end it wouldn't have made any
real difference if McCain had won. Uh
you know, Obama turned out to be a
massive wararmonger, too. Um he ended up
not delivering on his key promise for a
public option in the Affordable Care Act
and he he betrayed us all. I mean I
wrote a book called about all about his
betrayals called the book of Obama and
you know he was a remarkably right-wing
man who's passed off he but he plays a
liberal on TV. Disgusting. Thanks Reed.
Thanks Star. Appreciate it. Um voting
for a third party. Cameron wants to
know, "What's the thought process beind
if you know they'll never win or change
much?" Well, it's first of all, I don't
want them to change. I uh want them to
win. Um the way I look at it is uh
voting is really a very simple act. You
vote for the candidate or party that
you'd like to see win. And if you don't
want to see them, if you wake up on
election day and your person wins and
you're not excited, you shouldn't have
voted for them. And so you, you know,
people talk about we need a third party.
Everyone agrees we need a third party or
a fourth or a fifth or a sixth. Well,
okay. So, if you believe that, then
support them. Give them money. Uh, you
know, volunteer for them and vote for
them. And if you don't believe that,
then like don't say you believe in a
third party. I mean the voting
strategically is also inane and stupid
because literally there is zero chance
that your one vote which is all you can
control is going to change the outcome
in any state at all much less a state a
key swing state but there's no way and
people will say well if everybody thinks
that way okay but the point is we're not
you can only control yourself we can't
you know we do work in in in as a group
but we work as a group individ
individually. So, I just don't think
that it's like that. Yes, indeed. Don't
forget to like and subscribe. Much
appreciated. Um, okay. And I think now
I'm going to call it because this is a
full show. Thanks so much everybody for
watching and following the show. Uh,
John Kiryaku and I will both be back for
a full show tomorrow, 5:00 PM Eastern
time. We'll be back next week, Monday
through Friday. But don't miss tomorrow.
I'm sure we'll have a lot to talk about
after Trump and Putin uh have their
meeting. I have a feeling we'll probably
have a statement from them before the
show comes out. What with the time
difference and everything. Thanks you.
Thank you all for uh tuning in. Uh
please consider buying my latest book,
What's Left? Um it's called Never Mind
the Democrats, What's Left? It's
basically what would and what should a
real left demand? In other words, you
know, they're not. And uh really
appreciate you. Like, follow and share
the show. See you tomorrow.